{
  "quiz2": [
    {
      "question": "variables declared with in a class, outside any method, with the static keyword?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Local Variable",
        "Instance Variable",
        "Class Variable",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Class Variable",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "Class Variables are variables declared with in a class, outside any method, with the static keyword"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the default value of byte datatype in Java?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "0",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Default value of byte datatype is 0."
    },
    {
      "question": " Variables used in a switch statement can be used with which datatypes?(select three)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "string",
        "int",
        "char",
        "double",
        "float"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "string",
        "int",
        "char"
      ],
      "correct": [
        0,
        1,
        2
      ],
      "explanation": "Variables used in a switch statement can only be a string, enum, byte, short, int, or char"
    },
    {
      "question": "a class declared as private be accessed outside it's package?",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "false",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "No, it's not possible to accessed outside it's package."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is NOT an advantage of Java sockets?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Sockets are flexible and sufficient",
        "It cause low network traffic",
        "allows only to send packets of raw data between applications",
        "easily implemented for general communications"
      ],
      "answer": "allows only to send packets of raw data between applications",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": "The disadvantage is that Socket based communications allows only to send packets of raw data between applications."
    },
    {
      "question": "Polymorphism is the ability of an object to take on many forms.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Polymorphism is the ability of an object to take on many forms."
    },
    {
      "question": "An interface is a collection of abstract methods.",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "An interface is a collection of abstract methods. A class implements an interface, thereby inheriting the abstract methods of the interface."
    },
    {
      "question": "What is Multiple Inheritance?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "one class inheriting from more super classes",
        "more classes inheriting from one super class",
        "more classes inheriting from more super classes",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "one class inheriting from more super classes",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Multiple Inheritance is when one class inheriting from more super classes"
    },
    {
      "question": " A constructor ____?(select three)",
      "type": "checkboxes",
      "choices": [
        "Must have the same name as the class it is declared within",
        "Is used to create objects",
        "May be declared private",
        "Cannot be declared public"
      ],
      "answer": [
        "Must have the same name as the class it is declared within",
        "Is used to create objects",
        "May be declared private"
      ],
      "correct": [
        0,
        1,
        2
      ],
      "explanation": "A constructor is used is all those three ways"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "_____ is denoted by leading zero in java?",
      "answer": "octal numbers",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Octal Numbers are denoted by leading zero in java; ex. 04"
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "_____ is denoted by leading 0x or 0X in java?",
      "answer": "hexadecimal numbers",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Hexadecimal Numbers are denoted by leading 0x or 0X in java; ex. 0XF"
    },
    {
      "question": "To prevent any method from overriding, we declare the method as?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "final",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Final prevents methods from overriding"
    },
    {
      "question": "Break statement can be used as labels in Java",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "true",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Yes; ex. break one;"
    },
    {
      "question": "Java allows Default Arguments",
      "type": "true/false",
      "choices": [
        "true",
        "false"
      ],
      "answer": "false",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": "Java does not allow Default Arguments."
    },
    {
      "question": "Which method of the Component class is used to set the position and size of a component?",
      "type": "short answer",
      "choices": [],
      "answer": "setBounds()",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "setBounds() method is used"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is NOT true?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "An interface can extend another interface.",
        "A class which is implementing an interface must implement all the methods of the interface.",
        " An interface can implement another interface.",
        "An interface is a solution for multiple inheritance in java",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": " An interface can implement another interface.",
      "correct": 2,
      "explanation": " An interface can not implement another interface."
    },
    {
      "question": "Fill in the blank",
      "type": "fill in the blank",
      "choices": "In object-oriented programming, new classes can be defined by extending existing classes. This is an example of _____?",
      "answer": "inheritance",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Inheritance extends existing classes"
    },
    {
      "question": "Given a class named student, which of the following is a valid constructor declaration for the class?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "Student (student s) { }",
        "Student student ( ) { }",
        "Private final student ( ) { }",
        "Void student ( ) { }",
        "Static void student(){ }"
      ],
      "answer": "Student (student s) { }",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": " This is a valid constructor declaration for the class"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is a member of the java.lang package?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "List",
        "Queue",
        "Math",
        "Stack",
        "Process"
      ],
      "answer": "Queue",
      "correct": 1,
      "explanation": " Queue is a member of the java.lang package"
    },
    {
      "question": "Given the code\n\nString s1 = ”Hi” ;\nString s2 = ”Hi” ;\nString s3 = new String ( s1);\n\nWhich of the following would be true?",
      "type": "multiple choice",
      "choices": [
        "s1 == s2",
        "s1 = s2",
        "s3 == s1",
        "s3=s1",
        "s1!=s2"
      ],
      "answer": "s1 == s2",
      "correct": 0,
      "explanation": "Hi is equal to Hi; hence true."
    }
  ]
}
